<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Manitowoc Marine Band</title>
    <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Manitowoc Marine Band</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 13:42:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 13:42:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/schedule/</guid>
      <description>UPCOMING SCHEDULE document.addEventListener(&#39;DOMContentLoaded&#39;, function() { var options = { plugins: [ &#39;list&#39; ], header: false, defaultView: &#39;list&#39;, duration: { day: 365 }, events: { url: &#39;/event/index.json&#39; }, height: &#39;auto&#39;, navLinks: false }; new FullCalendar.Calendar(document.getElementById(&#39;calendar&#39;), options).render(); });   PAST EVENTS document.addEventListener(&#39;DOMContentLoaded&#39;, function() { var beginDate = new Date(); var endDate = new Date(); beginDate.setMonth(0); beginDate.setDate(1); endDate.setDate(endDate.getDate() - 1); var options = { plugins: [ &#39;list&#39; ], header: false, defaultView: &#39;list&#39;, events: { url: &#39;/event/index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact - Thanks</title>
      <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/contact_thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 21:01:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/contact_thanks/</guid>
      <description>CONTACT US Your message has been sent. We will try to get back to you as soon as possible!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 20:28:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/history/</guid>
      <description>HISTORY  The Manitowoc Marine Band was formed in the fall of 1898 by Frank Moser, a well-known local musician. Mr. Moser&amp;rsquo;s band quickly developed a reputation in the county and surrounding areas. Moser was at the helm of the Marine Band for fifteen years until his death in 1913. At that time the band was reorganized and band member Emil Sohrweide was elected director and manager. Mr. Sohrweide was to become the city&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;grand old man of music,&amp;rdquo; serving 43 years as director of the Manitowoc Marine Band, and 52 years as a band member.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CD</title>
      <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 20:13:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/cd/</guid>
      <description>CD  $10, available at:
 ACE Hardware Manitowoc Senior Center Roorbach’s Flowers Silver Lake College  Or by calling (920) 973-0604
Recorded out at Silver Lake College in July and August 2014, this CD features audience favorites from the 2012-2014 seasons. The recording showcases a wide variety of styles including marches, pop/musical theatre, vocal selections, holiday, patriotic, and more. Lifetime member Jeanmarie Stahl is featured on How Great Thou Art and God Bless the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Directors</title>
      <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/directors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 16:38:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/directors/</guid>
      <description>DIRECTORS Corey Van Sickle, director  Corey Van Sickle is the director of the Manitowoc Marine Band for the 2018 season. He received his bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree from UW-Eau Claire where he studied trombone with Dr. Philip Ostrander and conducting with Dr. Richard Mark Heidel. Corey has been a music educator in the area since 2008. He has taught at Roncalli High School, St. Francis Middle School, Manitowoc Public School District Summer Band Bash, and has taught numerous students privately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Around the World</title>
      <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/event/2019-06-13.around_the_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/event/2019-06-13.around_the_world/</guid>
      <description>The Manitowoc Marine Band is kicking off the season with a trip around the world. Every nation and culture around the world has a rich musical history and we are going to explore music from Russia, Scotland, England, Japan, Belgium, France, the Caribbean, and of course the good old USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auditions</title>
      <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/auditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/auditions/</guid>
      <description>AUDITIONS If interested in the Manitowoc Marine Band, please fill out the form below. The audition may be waived for those with extensive performing experience, or for high school students who attended State Solo &amp;amp; Ensemble (with a solo).
Audition consists of: prepared piece (solo or etude recommended), sight-reading, and scales up to 4 flats/sharps.
Name  Email Address  Primary Instrument  Secondary Instrument, if applicable  Phone Number  Musical Experience Please briefly describe your experience and accomplishments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Highlights</title>
      <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/event/2019-12-13.christmas_highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/event/2019-12-13.christmas_highlights/</guid>
      <description>Come early for a chili dinner and stay to celebrate the Christmas season with us as we play Christmas and Holiday Classics. We’ll play many of your favorite Christmas songs, and there may even be a visit from a certain resident of the North Pole!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/contact/</guid>
      <description> CONTACT US Your Name:    Email Address:   Message:      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cruiser Night</title>
      <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/event/2019-08-08.cruiser_night/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/event/2019-08-08.cruiser_night/</guid>
      <description>Bring your classic car and enjoy a night of music from the fifties, sixties and seventies. This is our annual concert and car show, with prizes awarded for the best cars. Music highlights include, Chicago: Pop and Rock Legends, car themed greats, music of Queen, as well as many others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fourth on the Shore</title>
      <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/event/2019-07-04.fourth_on_the_shore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/event/2019-07-04.fourth_on_the_shore/</guid>
      <description>Come celebrate the Fourth of July as the Marine Band celebrates our country with patriotic music. The Concert will feature E.E. Bagley’s National Emblem, Marches by Sousa and Fillmore, America the Beautiful, and many other favorites. Come see the band and stay for the reworks later in the evening!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kids Disney</title>
      <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/event/2019-07-26.kids_disney/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/event/2019-07-26.kids_disney/</guid>
      <description>This concert is great for kids or people that want to feel like a kid again. Join us as we play great music from Disney and children’s movies as well as other family friendly favorites. Highlights include How to Train Your Dragon, Pirates of the Caribbean, and many others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Season Highlights</title>
      <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/event/2019-07-10.season_highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/event/2019-07-10.season_highlights/</guid>
      <description>The Marine Band is hitting the road and playing in Central Park in Two Rivers. We are taking our favorite music from the season with us and performing in the “Cool City.” Come support the Marine Band as well as the Two Rivers Community Band as they provide concessions at the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Songs of Screen and Stage</title>
      <link>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/event/2019-06-27.songs_of_screen_and_stage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manitowocmarineband.org/event/2019-06-27.songs_of_screen_and_stage/</guid>
      <description>Some of the best music in the past century has been featured on screen in movies and on stage in musicals. The Marine Band will be performing some of the best including music by Rodgers and Hammerstein, The Jersey Boys, The Sound of Music, The Music Man, and many more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>